so search is one of the most important
services for any product and at Twitter
scale it becomes Ultra important but
what does it take to maintain search at
scale how can we ensure that a search
service continues to function no matter
what kind of load hits the system in
this video we dive deep into how Twitter
built its tooling around elasticsearch
that helps them handle massive surges in
search traffic do real time ingestion
and ingest hundreds of terabytes of data
in backfill but before we move forward
I'd like to talk to you about a course
on system design that I've been running
for over a year and a half now the
course is a code based course which
means I won't be rambling a solution and
it will not be a monologue at all
instead a small focused group of 50 to
16 genus will be brainstorming the
systems and designing it together this
way we build a very solid system and
learn from each other's experiences the
course is enrolled by 800 plus ingenious
spanning 12 codes and 12 countries
ingenious from companies like Google
Microsoft GitHub slack Facebook Tesla
Yelp Flipkart dream11 and many many many
more have taken this course and have
some wonderful things to say the course
is focused on Building Systems the way
they are built in the real world they
will be focusing heavily on building the
right intuition so that you are ready to
build any and every system out there we
will be discussing the trade-offs of
every single decision we make just like
how you do in your team we cover topics
ranging from Real Time text
communication for slack to designing our
own toilet balance live text commentary
to doing impressions counting at scale
in all we would be covering roughly 28
systems and the detailed curriculum
split week by week can be found in the
course page linked in the description
down below so if you are looking to
learn system design from the first
principles you will love this course I
have two offerings for you the first one
is the live cohort based course and the
second one is the recorded offering the
Live code base course happens once every
two months and will go on for eight
weeks while the recorded course contains
the recordings from one of the past
cohorts as is if you are in a hurry and
want to learn and want to binge learn
system design I would recommend going
you for the recorded one otherwise the
Live code is where you can participate
and discuss the systems and its design
life with me and the entire cohort the
decision is totally up to you the course
details prerequisites testimonials can
be found on the course page arpitbani
dot me slash masterclass I repeat
arpitbani dot me slash masterclass and I
would highly recommend you to check that
out I've also put the link of this
course page in the description down
below and I'm looking forward to see you
in my next cohort
so Twitter uses elasticsearch to power
search of their tweets users and direct
messages but why elasticsearch
elasticsearch provides speed it provides
scalability it is distributed in nature
which means scaling out is just adding
more nodes and more importantly it
provides very simple rest interface to
interface with it right because of the
simple rest apis what happens is you
just need a simple HTTP client to talk
to elasticsearch servers and it makes it
super easy to do so now before all the
tooling that they built at Twitter what
happened so every team was allowed to
spin up their elasticsearch clusters to
get their things done it's not just for
search but maybe for other use cases
they might use it for example real-time
aggregation real-time analytics and
whatnot
but because there were many clusters
like this the team owning that cluster
had the responsibility to set things up
correctly for example the because there
are multiple clusters there are multiple
teams owning it now who takes care of
sanitization some team enabled logs on
some clusters some team did not logs but
in a particular format there was no
throttling no rate limiting one team
interfacing with other like one team
abusing a cluster takes a cluster down
affects end users and whatnot so there
was a clear need that there had to be a
standardized way to set up a cluster
right but instead of just focusing on
setting up it is also about how people
are accessing the cluster so which is
where the first tooling that Twitter
built is an elasticsearch proxy now this
proxy sits between the client and the
elasticsearch cluster right so whoever
wants to talk to this elasticsearch
cluster cannot talk to this
elasticsearch cluster directly but has
to go through a proxy now this proxy is
a very simple HTTP client and but
because it is a simple HTTP client it
can piggyback a lot of stuff for example
this proxy because you know that all the
requests will go through this proxy to
any elasticsearch cluster now this proxy
you put in all sorts of metrics all
sorts of standardization that you would
need to do for example thirdly right you
don't want a lot of request coming from
a particular client to to take down the
elasticsearch cluster which is where
this proxy comes in which has a rate
limiter inbuilt right then routing you
might have multiple clusters who like
routing which request to wear take it's
taken care by this proxy right security
authentication right and more
importantly monitoring when it comes to
monitoring because this is a single
point of entry for anyone to talk to
elasticsearch now what happens you can
dump key metrics out of this proxy for
example what is the cluster Health what
is the success rate what is a failure
rate what is latencies and what not this
proxy's job was really important this
one layer that was added in within
obviously it shot the response time by a
fraction but this one centralized layer
helps them ensure that the access to
Cluster is standardized The Matrix that
are published are standardized the
logging is standardized authentication
standardized right this makes their this
increases the stability of the cluster
because not people are not directly
interfacing with elasticsearch right
really important now second thing that
can affect elasticsearch is injection
because given at Twitter scale there
would be huge amount of load coming onto
this elasticsearch clustered when a new
like for example a new tweet is posted
where right rather when a tweet is
posted it needs to be index in elastic
search right now there are millions of
tweets posted every minute now all of
those gets indexed in elasticsearch so
this means that there would be surge in
traffic Whenever there is a spike in
traffic at Twitter's usage right now
elasticsearch is little tricky to handle
such spikes and what happens is when
there is a sudden Spike elastic surge
does not get time to like like we do not
get time to spin up more nodes very
quickly because it takes time for the
data to move from here to there right
and elasticsearch is bad at handling
such searches two things that happen
typically is the indexing latency shoots
up and the query latency shoots up so it
like indexing the data into
elasticsearch becomes slower and firing
the search query on elasticsearch
becomes slower so all the key operations
take a hit now but at Twitter scale
spikes or surges are natural for example
if there is an event happening you would
see a lot of people tweeting about it at
that moment so there would be surge in
traffic depending on how real world
mimics but real world you cannot predict
what's happening in what would happen in
real world what would Trend at a
particular time so that is where Twitter
had to be very sure about handling
spikes handling searches so what did you
do instead of letting that thing
directly get ingested into elastic surge
they did it in an asynchronous way so
any right coming to be put into elastic
search now here it's more about that how
it used to happen was people used to
like directly call a pillar so the
client used to directly call
elasticsearch endpoint and used to put
the data but now there is one more layer
sitting before that which is like a
normal single topic Kafka that you have
like one topic for each cluster this is
what they have configured and the rights
are put into Kafka later to be consumed
by workers and then indexed it to
elasticsearch now what this ensures like
there might be one more Kafka before
that before it even comes here like
maybe from API server one Kafka taken to
this this is a proxy like so this is
what is done by the proxiliant so proxy
puts it in Kafka later to be consumed by
workers right so there is no direct
ingestion happening in elastic search
so this one step one step deferred is
what they did here it ensures that that
we are putting in data in a correct
streamlined way to elastic Source rather
than relying on something else so few
advantages over here first is request
matching you can very clearly see how we
have per topic uh one topic for each
elasticsearch cluster when you put in a
bulk of indexing request you can take
few at a time and make bulk calls to
elasticsearch reducing the lowest
non-elastic search second back pressure
given that if elastic search is slowing
due to any reason the workers can slow
things down very easily because elastic
search is not responding they can just
wait for some time before they start to
readjust the data right then retrace in
case there is a failure in case elastic
searches are due to any reason the right
request the injection is law is
basically queued up in this Kafka and
again later be consumed to be put into
elastic search so you get resiliency
just by adding this one more layer of
Kafka in between it ensures that we are
streamlining a consumption and ingestion
into elastic search right the next
service and really interesting one which
is where we see the entire architecture
together is a backfill service now it's
a very common requirement across
organizations that you will have to
backfill a lot of data into
elasticsearch this typically happens how
so for example you have a job which is
running which takes data from multiple
data sources and it wants to index them
into elasticsearch so typically what you
do you write a simple mapreduce job this
map reduce job would take data from
multiple sources and make calls like
each reducer will call elasticsearch
endpoints to get it indexed now this is
where the problem starts to creep in
when you have large number of reducers
running which is taking a lot of data
mappers taking a lot of data passing it
to reducers reduces ingesting into it
into elasticsearch in synchronous call
it would put load onto elasticsearch now
imagine transferring hundreds of
terabytes of data
elasticsearch would cry it is not
possible for elastic search to handle
such high like such huge ingestion in a
single chart
so which is where you have to do it in a
staggered way so how do you do it so
they already had a service which was a
map reduce job
whose job was to read data from multiple
sources when it was a backfill to read
data from multiple sources and the
reducers used to directly write to
elasticsearch but now what they do is
they read the data from multiple sources
the reducer instead of writing it
directly to elasticsearch they flush it
into an hdfs hello distributed file
system S3 any any compliant file system
would work hdfs S3 GCS pick your
favorite right so instead of their
service the map reduce instead of
writing it directly to elasticsearch
what this job did is this job it put it
into an hdfs
and then there were consumers who were
reading from it and then protected to
elasticsearch these are massive
ingestion happened right so let me walk
you through this architecture now how
how it beautifully solves the problem so
what they have is they created a proxy
for elasticsearch right so whenever
someone wants to talk to elasticsearch
it has to talk through this proxy so
request comes to this proxy proxy sees
if it's a read request read request
directly goes to elasticsearch right
there is no no points there you have to
because you your you want answer to your
query it will can only happen through
elasticsears so read directly goes to
elasticsearch now there is a write that
is happening in real time for example a
new tweet is created you want to ingest
this tweet in real time into
elasticsearch now some API server let's
say this is API server API server is
making a call to elasticsearch but what
it's doing it is not directly making
call to elasticsear because it's not
allowed to do so it is making a call to
the HTTP proxy a HTTP proxy instead of
directly writing to elasticsearch it
writes it it puts an event into Kafka
from this Kafka workers consume and it
puts it into elasticsearch right this
way real time ingestion happens in a
staggered way protecting an elastic
search cluster right so
like how users would a normally index
directly to elasticsearch is now changed
via this proxy which has very similar
interfaces elasticsearch but now it
happens in a staggered way and the more
important part around backfill where
they already had mapreduce job running
which was directly putting it into
elasticsearch now it takes like the HTTP
request that we're making to index the
data into elasticsearch now that same
request with that exact same payload
gets dumped into hdfs
from these workers pickup and then they
fire it into elasticsearch so there is
no there is not a lot of change to be
done from on the developer side of
things it's all seamless like no need to
change this map reduce job the only
thing like one small change that needs
to happen the map reducer where the
reducer is used to directly put it into
elasticsearch now they put it into hdfs
and a bunch of workers are spun
depending on the load or depending on
the data that was created the
orchestrator creates those very workers
and they consume the data from the https
and put it into elasticsearch right a
very seamless way now here you see a
pattern that the rights are always
deferred the rights are always made
asynchronous while the reads happen
synchronously and this is one of the
most common ways to build a scalable
system the way you do it is let the
Rights happen eventually but let the
reads happen synchronously especially in
a workload like this if it is a
non-transactional use case you defer it
all the time right so just to give you a
gist read happens synchronously to
elasticsearch Via this proxy the right
through this proxy goes through Kafka
consumed by workers put into
elasticsearch while the backfill the job
the map reduce job that used to directly
write it to elasticsearch now flushes it
into an hdfs which is consumed by
workers fund direct spun dynamically
using orchestrator and put into
elasticsearch right this is such a
beautiful piece of learning where we see
how rights which are differed makes your
system handle scale while reads happen
synchronously right you basically there
is no other way to do so right this is
such a beautiful piece of thing like how
Twitter at scale of Twitter how they are
ensuring that their elasticsearch
clusters don't go down while ensuring a
very nice standardization by adding this
proxiliary in front of it right great
this is all what I wanted to cover I
hope you found it interesting I hope you
found it amazing that is it for this one
I'll see you in the next one thanks
[Music]